In this lecture, we're going to look at the architectural decision point 9 which is observability
and monitoring.
In this lecture, we're going to look at bedrock observability and monitoring.
So you can monitor all aspects of your GenAI application built on Amazon bedrock using Amazon
CloudWatch.
Now, the second way to monitor your GenAI application built on Amazon bedrock is through
metrics.
So monitor the GenAI app performance using CloudWatch near real-time metrics.
So some of the common metrics that you may want to monitor is token count, input, and output
to manage cost, latency of the response, and errors that can help improve customer experience.
Then you can also set alarms that watch for certain thresholds and send notifications
or take actions when the value exceeds those thresholds.
So let's say you have a threshold where you want the model to generate the response within
two seconds.
So you can look at the latency of metrics and set a threshold of two seconds.
So if there are any responses that take more than two seconds, then it can generate
a alarm or take some downstream action.
Okay, now let's go and take a look at some of the metrics available in CloudWatch for Amazon
bedrock.
So first you have the invocation.
So the unit will be sample count.
And here you can take a look at model invocation logging where you can collect invocation logs,
model input, data basically prompt, output data for all the invocation.
Then second we have the invocation latency, which is measured in milliseconds.
And here you can track the latency of the invocation.
So this is important as we discussed for customer experience, you can track the latency of
the invocation.
Then you can track the invocation client errors, invocation server errors, and you can
get the sample count.
Then you can look at invocation throttling again, number invocation that the system throttled.
So if there is a lot of throttling, then you can look at cross region inferencing.
Then you have the input token count.
Again, this is important metrics if you want to track the cost.
And for any production grid application, this is a really important metrics.
Then your legacy model invocation, if you're using a legacy model, let's say you are using
a legacy model from entropic or any other model product, then you can track that.
Then you have the output token count and output image count.
Again this can be used for cost tracking.
Then you can finally also track the output image count.
So if your model is generating images, then you can track this metric as well.
And now you can also monitor Amazon bedrock guardrails using cloud watch metrics.
So you can see your invocation number request to apply guardrails API operation.
Invocation latency, so latency of the invocation.
So if you're using guardrails, you can check if it is increasing the latency for your
invocation.
So there will be some latency from the model, but guardrails can also add on to that latency.
So you can see here, there are different metrics that you can track using cloud watch metrics
for guardrails.
Now just to summarize, there are three different ways in which you can monitor your journey
applications using cloud watch.
So first is the metrics.
So we've already looked at different cloud watch metrics.
Then we have the logs, cloud watch logs, and we saw that there is full invocation logging,
input prompt, output, and a lot of metadata.
And then finally, you can also use log queries for creating a dashboard or getting custom
insights.
And this can be done using cloud watch log insights, so query and analyze logs, not metrics.
So here's an example that I was trying out.
So I sent some prompt to Amazon Nova Pro, and then it generated logs.
And then I just wrote a query in this logs insight, you can see here, what I was trying
to do is get a view of the input token count and the output token count.
So I created this query, ran this query, and this is the summary that it generated.
Okay, so that's pretty much it from this lecture.
I'll see in the next lecture.
Thank you.